Guide to the Snider Family Papers, 1912-1938 (bulk 1914-1918)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Snider Family Papers
1912-1938
1914-1918
Snider Family
1.4 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence from Mary and Marguerite Snider (VC 1918) to their parents and brother Frank that tell of the day-to-day life of Vassar students, their classes, extra-curricular activities, and social life. Also includes letters to and from Frank that tell a similar story of his days at Mercersburg Academy in Pennsylvania and Amherst College in Massachusetts.
Biographical Note
Twins Mary and Marguerite Snider graduated from Vassar in 1918. Born December 20, 1895 in Uniontown, Pennsylvania to Frank and Hannah (Happie) L. Snider, they returned to Uniontown after their graduation. Both Mary and Marguerite worked with the Red Cross during World War and after, Marguerite until 1925 and Mary until at least 1947. Marguerite earned a certificate in economic research and community organization at Bryn Mawr in 1921 and her C.L.U. from the College of Life Underwriters. She worked as an underwriter for the Equitable Life Assurance Society beginning in 1925. She married attorney Buell B. Whitehill in 1945, and died in October 1980.
Mary Snider did not marry and lived at the family home on Kensington Avenue in Uniontown until at least 1960. Alumnae surveys in 1947 and 1956 indicate that she was the Home Service Secretary of the American Red Cross’s Fayette County chapter. In 1960, she reported that she was the part-time Executive Secretary of the Mental Health Association of Fayette County. She retired in 1971, and died in 1997.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains correspondence from Mary and Marguerite Snider to their parents and brother Frank that tell of the day-to-day life of Vassar students, their classes, extra-curricular activities, and social life. Also included are letters to and from Frank that tell a similar story of his days at Mercersburg Academy in Pennsylvania and Amherst College in Massachusetts.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Student Materials Collection
Subject Headings
Names:
Snider, Marguerite Lyons; Snider, Mary Lyons; Snider, Frank
Organizations:
Amherst College--Students; Vassar College--Students; Mercersburg Academy--Students
Document Types:
Correspondence
VCL Categories:
Family; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Original encoding by Jessica Kemm, November 2009.
Updated by Emma Gronbeck, November 2025.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary and Jacob Leed, August 2009. (M2009-026) An additional accession, folders 2.10-2.11, was given in April 2010 (M2010-009).
Series List
- Series I. Marguerite Snider
  This series includes letters to and from Marguerite Snider, as well as official Vassar College documents and correspondence.
- Series II. Mary Snider
  This series includes letters to and from Mary Snider, as well as official Vassar College documents and correspondence.
- Series III. Frank Snider
  This series includes letters to and from Frank Snider, as well as correspondence related to his academic record and documents regarding his military training.
- Series IV. Miscellaneous
  This series includes letters to and from brother Joe Snider and to mother Hannah (Happie) Snider as well as other miscellaneous correspondence.
Container List
- Series I. Marguerite Snider
  - Vassar documents and correspondence, 1912-1920 (Folder 1.1)
  - To parents and brothers, Frank and Joe, 1914 Sep-Dec (Folder 1.2)
  - To parents and brother Frank, 1915 Jan-1916 Apr (Folders 1.3-1.6)
  - To parents and brother Frank, 1916 Apr-Jul (Folder 2.10)
  - To parents, 1916 Oct-1918 Jun (Folders 1.7-1.10)
  - To Frank Snider at Mercersburg Academy and Amherst, 1916-1918 (Folder 1.11)
- Series II. Mary Snider
  - Vassar documents and correspondence, 1912-1918 (Folder 1.12)
  - To parents and brother Frank, 1914 Sep-1916 Dec (Folders 1.13-1.17)
  - To parents and brother Frank, 1916 Apr-Jul (Folder 2.11)
  - To parents, 1917 Jan-1918 Mar (Folders 1.18-1.21)
  - To parents, 1918 Apr-Jun, 1920 (Folder 1.22)
  - To Frank Snider at Mercersburg and Amherst, 1916-1918 (Folder 2.1)
- Series III. Frank Snider
  - Parents and friends to Frank Snider, 1914-1919 (Folders 2.2-2.3)
  - From Frank Snider, 1917-1920 (Folders 2.4-2.6)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous
  - To and from Joe Snider, 1915-1917 (Folder 2.7)
  - To Mrs. Frank (Hannah/Happie) Snider, 1916-1918 (Folder 2.8)
  - To Mrs. Frank (Hannah/Happie) Snider, 1937-1938 (Folder 2.8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1916-1920 (Folder 2.9)